翻译  草草
时间轴  Ans
顾问  老杜
后期  饿得慌
校对  草草
总监  草草
第四季  第二集
纸牌屋
人人影视倾情奉献
今晚戴我母亲的耳环欢迎回来弗兰西斯
2016国情咨文
他是个没有格调  没有风度  没有羞耻的蛮人
He is a classless, graceless, shameless barbarian.
他那么对你  伊丽莎白  简直恶心
What he did to you, Elizabeth, it was disgusting.
-可怕  -太过分了
- Awful. - Just vile.
-能递给我那盘...  -好
- Can you pass the plate of... - Yeah.
可你为什么没告诉我们
But why didn't you tell us?
一想到那么多年来  你一个人抵抗病魔
The thought of you fighting this alone, all those years...
我不希望人可怜
I didn't want pity.
他们真的吵架了吗
Is it true that they were arguing?
不  她是南下来陪我的
No, she came down here to be with me.
当然  我们没想到
Of course, we didn't expect
这事会被当众说出去
that it was gonna be made a public display.
他大概觉得那样最能打消传言吧
I guess he thought that was the best way to dispel the rumors.
那人不配当总统
That man does not deserve to be president.
我一向不愿说他坏话  伊丽莎白
I've never wanted to speak ill of him, Elizabeth,
但我一想到他是怎么对待你和克莱尔的
but when I think of the way he's treated you and Claire...
行了  他还是她的女婿呢
Oh, stop now. He is still her son-in-law.
不  芭说得对
No, Bar's right.
他不配当总统
He doesn't deserve to be president.
你们...其实都可以帮我
You could... all help me, actually.
-什么都行  -随你说
- Anything. - Just say the word.
希瑟·邓巴
Heather Dunbar.
我们该支持她
We should be supporting her.
用我们的支票支持
With our checkbooks.
你真心希望他输吗
You really want him to lose?
等他输了  克莱尔就能开启自己的事业了
When he loses, Claire can begin her own career...
这对我来说更加重要
which is far more important to me.
我不知道我们是不是能起到作用  但是
I don't know if we can really make a difference, but...
我想做点比坐在这儿说他坏话更实际的事
I'd rather do more than just sit around and bad-mouth him.
那么  我们就写张支票吗
So, we just write a check?
不能让弗兰西斯知道
Now, Francis can't know.
我们的捐助得...曲线救国
I mean, our donations will have to be... once removed.
那项修正案已经拖延多年了
That amendment has stalled for years.
因为我们在退休军人事务处没人
Because we didn't have someone in Veterans Affairs.
这不是退休军人问题  是公共卫生问题
It isn't a veterans issue. It's public health.
这不是我的强项
That's not my specialty.
等等  你是说
Wait, you're telling me
你不认识任何得过乳腺癌的人吗
you don't know anyone who's had breast cancer?
我是指立法方面
I mean in terms of legislation.
多50%
Fifty percent more.
黑人女性患乳腺癌后
That's how many more black women
死亡率比白人女性高50%
die of breast cancer than white women.
在我们选区  比率高于谋杀率
In our district, it's higher than the murder rate.
帮我们拿下诊所
Help us get this clinic.
我并不否认这一问题的重要性
I don't deny that it's an important issue,
但我得选好自己支持什么
but I have to pick and choose what I support.
你在家乡的竞选选情严峻  议员女士
You're in a tight race back home, Congresswoman.
我们可以建立超级政治行动委员会
We'll set up a super PAC.
三百万美元
Three million dollars.
你没跟我谈就这么做了
You did this without talking to me?
克莱尔和我好好谈过了  母亲
Claire and I spoke at length, Mother.
克莱尔
Claire?
你对第一夫人都直呼其名了啊
You're calling the First Lady by her given name, now?
希望你也可以如此  议员女士
Well, and I would hope you would, too, Congresswoman.
你背着我行动  安德伍德夫人
You went behind my back, Mrs. Underwood.
我不是求你全力支持我
I'm not asking for a full endorsement.
我只是求你允许西莉娅延迟竞选
I'm just asking for your blessing on Celia delaying her run.
当然  也保证不会跟我竞争
And of course, a promise to not campaign against me.
杰姬·夏普很支持邓巴
Jackie Sharp's big on Dunbar.
她为什么要帮你
Why would she help you?
这笔钱跟我们不直接挂钩
This money isn't directly linked to us.
你是说总统乐意
You mean the president's comfortable
给杰姬送竞选经费吗
putting money in Jackie's war chest?
是的  但我们得保密
He is, but we have to keep this quiet.
你们两个办公室之间绝对不能有联络
There can't be any communication between your office and his.
-讲话  -赛斯把最新的改动加进去了
- Speech? - Seth put in your latest edits.
等您批准了  我们就拿给提词器的人
Once you approve, we'll send it to the teleprompters.
-她到了吗  -几分钟前刚到
- Has she arrived yet? - A few minutes ago.
请坐
Please sit down.
如果杰姬退缩  我们不能给她留后路
If Jackie gets cold feet, we can't leave her any choice.
我已经在处理了
I'm already on top of that.
怎么处理
How?
他们总去同一家酒店
They always use the same hotel.
我找人在街对面守着了
I've got a guy set up across the street.
你会小心行事吧
I'm assuming you're being careful.
我不是单纯的技术员  我也会老法子
I'm not just a tech outfit. I can go old school, too.
女士  我们为您备好了午餐
Ma'am? We have lunch prepared for you.
真是气派
This is impressive.
趁现在好好瞻仰一下吧  我们一会儿就走
Well, soak it up while you can. We won't be here long.
我就回来
I'll be right back.
阿纳托利·罗斯卓波夫  他的帝国价值300亿
Anatoly Rostropov. His empire's worth 30 billion.
佩特罗夫昨晚叫人杀了他
Petrov had him killed last night.
史坦尼斯拉夫·乌斯特拉维奇
Stanislav Ustravich,
特卡斯石油的创始人
founder of Turkas Oil.
今早早些时候被发现身亡
Found dead early this morning.
伊戈尔·米尔金  媒体大亨  身价240亿
Igor Milkin, media tycoon worth 24 billion.
被政府没收了
Very outspoken against Petrov
电视台和报社后一直公开抨击佩特罗夫
after the government seized his TV stations and newspapers.
两小时前  他的私人飞机在缅因州班格尔降落
His private plane landed in Bangor, Maine, two hours ago.
我们在停机坪上隔离了他
We've got him quarantined on the tarmac.
他寻求政治庇护  说担心自己有生命危险
He's seeking political asylum. Says he's in fear for his life.
我们认为他们一直在密谋推翻佩特罗夫
We believe they've been formulating a plan to unseat Petrov.
布鲁特斯  卡西乌斯  还有那个逃脱的家伙[刺杀凯撒]
Brutus, Cassius, and the one that got away.
莫斯科坚决要我们马上把他送回去
Moscow's adamant we send him back immediately.
那就送他回去
Then send him back.
我不希望国情咨文被
I don't want the State of the Union
庇护纠纷盖过风头
overshadowed by some asylum dispute.
他是佩特罗夫的麻烦  不关我们的事
He's Petrov's problem, not ours.
从法律上讲  先生
Legally, sir,
我们有义务处理他的庇护请求
we are obligated to process his asylum request.
-媒体不是已经知道了吧  -不  先生
- Don't tell me the press knows he's here. - No, sir.
他们一进入美国领空
We jammed communications on his plane
我们就屏蔽了他飞机的通讯
as soon as it entered U.S. airspace.
那不就没有问题了吗
Then we don't have a problem, do we?
如果我们送他回去  他很可能会被杀
It's likely he'll be killed if we send him back.
那又如何  他想屠龙  又没打中
So be it. He tried to slay a dragon and he missed the mark.
现在他得面对怒火了
Now he's gotta face the fire.
我们担心会发生更多杀戮  更多公司被查抄
Our fear is more killings, more company seizures.
会导致银行挤兑
That leads to a run on the banks,
卢布崩溃  债务违约
collapse of the ruble, default on debts.
我们已经知道
And we already know
他一直在跟国际货币基金组织暗中联络
he's been back-channeling about a bailout
讨论救市计划
with the IMF.
你如果有提议  就快点说
Well, if you have a proposal to make, then make it quickly.
-我还得准备讲话呢  -是  先生
- I have a speech to prep for. - Yes, sir.
去年您穿的是灰褐色  或许这件太像了
Last year you wore the taupe, so maybe this is too similar?
请进
Come in.
我接通了黑尔太太的电话
I was able to get Mrs. Hale on the phone.
太好了  能让我们单独待会儿吗
Oh, great. Uh, could you excuse me for a moment?
-母亲  -您没事吧  黑尔太太
- Mother? - You doing okay, Mrs. Hale?
是的  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
那是谁
Who was that?
我奖励自己做美甲呢
I'm treating myself to a pedicure.
没人能听到我
Nobody can hear me.
你想谈谈吗
You wanted to talk?
是的  我想感谢你  感谢你的帮助
Yes, I wanted to thank you, for all of your help.
看来议员女士倾向于同意了
Uh, it looks like the congresswoman is leaning toward a yes.
我在想  等你竞选时
You know, I was thinking, when you run,
你该用你的娘家姓
you should use your maiden name instead.
母亲  我不能那么做  面子上过不去
Mother, I couldn't do that. It would look bad.
那可不可以...
Well, then how about if you...
叫克莱尔·黑尔-安德伍德
if you use Claire Hale-Underwood?
这听上去挺不错的
That has a nice ring to it.
或许吧
Maybe.
-你见他了吗  -还没
- Have you seen him yet? - No, not yet.
你今晚打算穿什么
What are you gonna wear tonight?
其实我正在考虑呢
I was just deciding that now, actually.
希望是件深色的
Something dark, I hope.
要么是黑色  要么是象牙白  老实说
Well, it's between black and ivory, and to tell you the truth,
象牙白这件美极了
this ivory is so beautiful--
老天爷  别穿象牙白
Oh, for God's sakes, don't wear ivory.
就算是你那样的身材
Even with your figure,
也只会突出各种不该突出的地方
it'll accentuate all the wrong places.
你会看讲话吗
Are you going to watch the speech?
母亲
Mother?
嗯  我...
Yes, I'm gonna...
我会让迈克尔在卧室里摆台电视
I'm gonna have Michael put a TV in the bedroom.
安德伍德夫人  总统在等您了
Mrs. Underwood, the president is ready for you.
我就出去
I'll be right out.
母亲  我得挂了
Mother, I have to go.
嗯  当然  你肯定很忙
Yes, I-- Of course. I'm sure you must be very busy.
回家见
I'll see you when I get home?
如果我睡了
If I'm asleep...
那我们早上见
Then I'll see you in the morning.
再见  母亲
Goodbye, Mother.
再见  穿黑的那件
Bye. Wear the black!
这事绝不能泄露出去
I don't want even the slightest chance this gets out.
我们设了警戒线  机尾号也会遮住
We set up a perimeter. And we'll cover the tail number.
很好  跟佩特罗夫约好讲话后通话
Good. Set up a call with Petrov, for after the speech.
那时莫斯科是凌晨五点
It'll be 5:00 a.m. in Moscow.
他肯定会看的
Oh, I guarantee he'll be watching.
先生  您得接一下
Sir? I think you should take this.
失陪
Excuse me.
你好  议员女士
Hello, Congresswoman.
抱歉来晚了  请坐
Sorry for the delay. Please sit down.
你收到耳环了吗
Did you get the earrings?
是的  谢谢
I did. Thank you.
我母亲的  两克拉钻石
My mother's. Two-carat diamonds.
今晚戴吧
For tonight.
没什么比得上钻石耳环了
There's nothing quite like diamond earrings.
我们开始吧
Shall we begin?
今年  我们要改变一下出场方式
Uh, this year, we're handling the arrival a bit differently.
您将先被护送去圆形大厅与领导层合影
You'll be escorted to the rotunda for a photo op with the leadership
然后再去等候室
before going to the holding room.
我不需要去等候室
I don't need to go to the holding room.
你直接带我去大厅吧
You can take me directly to the gallery.
没关系  都听第一夫人的
Yes, that's fine. Whatever the First Lady prefers.
之后我们需要分两个车队
And we'll need two separate motorcades after.
我要直接去机场
I'll be going straight to the airport.
-那就两个车队  -是  先生
- Two motorcades, then. - Yes, sir.
我想向你们汇报一下特别来宾名单
I'd like to brief you on the list of special guests attending--
看上去没什么问题
This all seems pretty straightforward.
如果你觉得没问题我也没问题
I'm good if you are.
嗯  没问题  多谢你了
Yes, I'm fine. Thank you so very much.
你有空吗
Do you have a moment?
伊丽莎白怎么样了
How's Elizabeth?
她让我代她问好
She sends her regards.
当然了
I'll bet she does.
竞选呢
And the campaign?
还在试探
Still exploring viability.
桃瑞丝还没答应吗
Doris isn't on board yet?
回头就知道了
Uh, we'll see.
你给了她什么
What have you offered her?
我想先跟莉安策划一个稳妥的竞选策略
Well, I want to put together a solid campaign strategy with LeAnn
再跟她二次接触
before engaging her again.
如果你需要我帮忙  就告诉我
Well, if you need my help, let me know.
我当党鞭时  我们关系很好
She and I were very close when I was whip.
-你的事够多了  -不麻烦的
- You've got a lot on your plate. - No, it's no trouble at all.
我再找你吧
I'll let you know.
今晚见
See you tonight.
可以开始准备了吗  先生
You ready to prep, sir?
我要做些改动
I need to make some changes.
我去叫讲稿撰写人
I'll call the speech writers.
不用  我自己来  去把克丽丝塔找来
No, I wanna do these myself. And track down Calista.
我们还得再加一名宾客
We have to make room for one more guest.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
怎么回事
What's that?
我要把文身洗掉
I'm having it removed.
太可惜了  我挺喜欢呢
Well, that's too bad. I liked it.
该向前看了
Hmm, time to move on.
你想放下什么
From what?
需要文身的我
From the me that needed a tattoo.
我没多少时间
I don't have much time.
你什么时候得去国会大厦
When do you have to be at the Capitol?
不到一小时后
Less than an hour.
-威士忌还是伏特加  -伏特加
- Whiskey or vodka? - Vodka.
你对桃瑞丝·琼斯有多了解
How well do you know Doris Jones?
见过她几次  不怎么了解
Oh, uh, met her a few times. I don't know her that well, though.
-怎么  -她女儿  西莉娅
- Why? - Her daughter, Celia,
希望我帮他们弄到拨款
wants me to help them get appropriations
筹建一家乳腺癌诊所
for a breast cancer clinic.
作为回报  他们愿用德州的钱资助我的竞选
In return, they want to pad my campaign with Texas money.
-多少  -三百万
- How much? - Three million.
可能还不止
To start.
她的选区才没那么多钱
Her district doesn't have that kind of money.
西莉娅说他们的捐助人是30区以外的
Celia says they're courting donors from outside the 30th.
但我一个助手
But one of my aides
听说克莱尔·安德伍德和莉安·哈维
heard that Claire Underwood and LeAnn Harvey
今天去了琼斯的办公室
were in Jones' office today.
莉安我认识
LeAnn's someone I know.
格兰顿-希尔几年前想把她挖来
Glendon Hill was courting her a few years ago.
她拒绝了你吗
Did she turn you down?
我们请不起她
We couldn't afford her.
我知道你已经金盆洗手了  但这笔钱不是小数
Look, I know you're out of the game, but this is a lot of money.
如果是真  能帮我大忙  如果不是...
If it's legit, it could really help me. But if it's not, I--
我去跟莉安谈谈  看能问出什么来
I'll talk to LeAnn and see what I can find out.
给
Here.
我想先尝你
I want to taste you first.
下面是特别报道
This is a special report.
弗兰西斯·安德伍德总统向国会联席会议
President Francis Underwood's State of the Union address
发表国情咨文讲话
to a joint session of Congress.
今晚  世界的眼睛都盯着华盛顿
Tonight the eyes of the world are on Washington.
安德伍德总统几分钟后就将上台
President Underwood will take the stage in just a few minutes...
把食物拿走
Take the food away.
您午饭就没吃  黑尔太太
You didn't eat your lunch, Mrs. Hale.
我不舒服
Yeah, well, I didn't feel well.
那您就更该吃点晚饭了  您的药
Then you really should eat dinner. Your medication--
别让我再说一遍了  迈克尔
Please don't make me ask you again, Michael.
拿走  这味儿熏得我难受
Just take it away. The smell of it is making me ill.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
女士们先生们  美国第一夫人
Ladies and gentlemen, the First Lady of the United States.
-西莉娅  -谢谢你的安排
- Celia. - Thank you so much for arranging this.
能坐在你旁边太荣幸了
It's a big honor to be sitting next to you.
议长先生  有请美国总统
Mr. Speaker, the President of the United States.
在这里看国情咨文真有意思
Interesting place to watch the SOTU.
这样更好玩  跟人民大众在一起
It's more fun this way. You know, hanging with the hoi polloi.
你为什么来华府
So, what brings you to D.C.?
国会都到齐了  适合揽活儿干
Well, all of Congress in town, it's good for hustling work.
你什么时候揽过活儿  你从来都是拒绝别人
Since when do you hustle? You turn people away.
你怎么知道我在这儿
How'd you know I was in town?
我虽然退休了  但还是眼观六路耳听八方
I might be retired, but I still have my ear to the ground.
是真的喽  伟大的雷米·丹顿解甲归田了
So that's true? The great Remy Danton has hung up his jersey?
我从未这么痛快过
I've never felt better.
-你不是来跟我寒暄的吧  -不是
- Don't tell me this is a social visit. - No.
-如果不是为公事  -是公事
- Well, if it isn't business... - It's business.
-各位国会议员  -好吧
- Members of Congress... - Okay.
-我十分荣幸  -那么
- ...I have the high privilege... - So...
-等等  节目开始了  -为各位请出
- Oh, hold on. The show is starting. - ...of presenting to you,
美国总统
the President of the United States.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
谢谢  议长先生  副总统先生
Thank you. Mr. Speaker, Mr. Vice President,
各位国会议员  我的美国同胞们
members of Congress, my fellow Americans.
一年前
One year ago,
我第一次做这番讲话
when I gave this address for the first time,
当时我国处于完全不同的一个时期
it was during a very different period for our country.
我国正在从一起政治丑闻和
Our nation was recovering from a political scandal
与中国的贸易危机中走出来
and a trade crisis with China.
而你们面前的  是一位未经过选举的总统
Before you stood a president no one had elected.
但现在  那个人依然站在你们面前
But that same man stands before you now,
而黑暗时期已经过去
and the darkness is behind us.
国家现在情势大好  前途愈发光明
The state of the union is bright, and getting brighter.
我们遭遇过挑战  没错
We've had our challenges, yes.
尤其是跟俄罗斯
Particularly with Russia.
的确有些很紧张的时刻
There were some tense moments, to be sure,
但我们还是克服了那些紧张
and yet we overcame those tensions.
佩特罗夫总统让我们继续建立信任
President Petrov let us continue to build trust
并表现出我们已从去年的经历中吸取了教训
and show that we've learned from our experiences last year.
我个人想感谢第一夫人
And I'd personally like to acknowledge the First Lady,
她为修复两国关系带了路
who led the way in repairing those burned bridges.
她得到的掌声比总统还多
She's getting more applause than the president.
对你是好事吧
Good for you, isn't it?
好厉害的客户
Quite a high-profile client.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
只是一猜
Just a guess.
不  你猜错了
No, you guessed wrong.
你知道有财大气粗的德州捐助人
So what do you know about big Texas donors...
就为了达拉斯一个穷选区
who care enough about a poor Dallas district
会给加州的竞选捐钱吗
to donate money to a campaign in California?
我没听说过
That went right over my head.
第一夫人去了达拉斯  你当时也在那儿
First Lady was in Dallas. You were in Dallas.
第一夫人来了这儿
The First Lady is here.
你也来了
Now you're here.
我觉得你是太闲了  雷米
I think you have far too much time on your hands, Remy.
这笔钱上到处是你的痕迹
Your fingerprints are all over this money.
你现在为杰姬·夏普工作了
You're working for Jackie Sharp now?
不  只是朋友
No. Just friends.
-只是朋友吗  -嗯
- Just friends, huh? - Yeah.
我觉得她身上也到处是你的痕迹
I think your fingerprints are all over her.
这样如何
How about this?
你别来刺探我的事
You don't poke around in my shit...
我就不去刺探你的
and I won't poke around in yours.
见到你很高兴  雷米  别退休就变怂了
It was good to see you, Remy. Don't get too soft in retirement.
一般来说
Now, it's considered uncouth
正在进行竞选的总统
for a president who's in the midst of a campaign,
不该直接谈论即将到来的竞选  但今晚
to talk directly about the upcoming election, but tonight,
我觉得我必须谈
I feel compelled.
因为我们选民即将在
Because the votes our electorate casts
目前的初选和11月的大选中投的票
during the current primaries and the general election in November
将对在座的各位有深远的影响
will have a profound impact on everyone in this room.
有些人  包括我  可能将失业
Some of us, myself included, may find ourselves out of a job.
如果我们想保住工作
If we want to keep our jobs,
我们就得聆听美国民众的声音
we have to listen to the American people.
我们就得更加努力  说到做到
We have to work harder! We have to deliver!
就像桃瑞丝·琼斯
Just like Doris Jones.
她已经在国会任职了34年
She has kept her job in Congress for 34 years
因为她从未向逆境低过头
because she never relented in the face of adversity.
事实上  就在今天  她还为一家她已经争取了
In fact, just today, she called me about a breast cancer clinic
十年的乳腺癌诊所给我打了电话
she has been fighting for over the past decade.
她的计划很大胆
Now, her plan is bold.
将退伍军人医院扩张  向普通民众开放
A VA hospital expansion open to the general public,
由联邦资金资助
financed by federal money.
这一大胆计划能通过科普  筛查
A bold plan that will significantly increase successful diagnoses
和可负担医保  大幅提升确诊和治疗的成功率
and treatment through education, screenings, and affordable care.
她一次次遭遇阻力
Now, she's gotten resistance, time and again...
来自退伍军人事务处的阻力
from the Veterans Affairs administration,
来自她国会同事的阻力
from her colleagues in Congress...
-能调大声点吗  -来自那些不希望
- Can you turn it up a bit? - ...from those who don't want to see
政府给计划生育组织拨款的人
government funds going to Planned Parenthood.
但是  她今天打给我时
And yet, when she called me today,
她对建立这家诊所的热忱
she was just as passionate about this clinic
一如十年前她第一次跟我提出时那般
as she was when she first brought it up to me ten years ago.
桃瑞丝  你成功了
Well, Doris, it worked.
我会跟退伍军人事务部长
I'll be working with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs,
住房和城市发展部以及国会领袖合作帮你建立诊所
HUD and the congressional leaders to get you that clinic.
因为你  我们将拯救生命
Because of you, we'll save lives.
这正是美国人民想看到的领导
And that is exactly the sort of leadership the American people want.
更多桃瑞丝·琼斯这样的领导人
More leaders like Doris Jones.
等她本届任期结束退休时
And when she retires at the end of this term,
我很高兴她女儿西莉娅
I'm delighted to say that her daughter, Celia,
将竞选缺职
will run for the open seat
像她母亲那样  继续实现人民的愿望
to continue delivering just like her mother has.
不会吧
No fucking way.
我本人会
And I, for one, will support
百分百支持你的竞选
your candidacy with everything I've got.
我知道克莱尔也会的
And I know Claire will, as well.
德州人百折不挠
Texans are tenacious.
我很骄傲我娶了一位
I'm proud to be married to one,
我很骄傲曾与琼斯议员女士
and I'm proud to have served with one,
这样的德州人共事过
like Congresswoman Jones.
谢谢你  桃瑞丝  谢谢你多年的服务
Thank you, Doris, for all your years of service,
也谢谢你  西莉娅  继承母亲的衣钵
and thank you, Celia, for picking up the mantle.
桃瑞丝说是她女儿说话冒失
Doris said her daughter spoke out of turn,
她对她和安德伍德协商的交易并不知情
that she didn't know about the deal she was brokering with Underwood.
你跟莉安联络上了吗
Did you connect with LeAnn?
没有
No, I didn't.
她说她得明天才能见我
She said she couldn't meet until tomorrow.
现在也没必要了
Well, I guess there's no point now, anyway.
如果是白宫在准备筹款
If the White House is orchestrating the funding,
安德伍德肯定不需要我帮忙
Underwood's not gonna want my help.
该死  那笔钱本来能帮大忙的
Fuck! I really could've used that money.
如果看上去像天上掉馅饼
Well, when it looks too good to be true...
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我什么时候能再见你
When am I gonna see you again?
我不知道
I don't know.
我有点...闷得发疯
I've been... feeling a bit stir-crazy.
如果我退休了  或许该出去走走
If I'm retired, I should probably travel some.
你可以去加州啊
Well, you could travel to California.
11月之前  我会更多待在那边
I'll be there more than here until November.
或许吧
Yeah, maybe.
不去也行
Or don't.
你知道怎么联系我
You know how to reach me.
你觉得是雷米吗
Do you think it was Remy?
不太可能  我让他知道我们知道了
Highly doubtful. I made it clear what we knew.
他知道你有证据吗
He knows you have proof?
他知道我知道  不知道我有证据
He knows that I know. Not that I have proof.
或许我们不该这就把那张牌打出去
Maybe we shouldn't have played that card yet.
雷米把事情都串起来了
Remy was connecting the dots.
我必须让他打住
I needed to put the brakes on him.
如果不是他
Well, if it wasn't him,
那肯定是桃瑞丝自己去找了弗兰西斯
Doris must've gone to Francis himself.
她看到了机会就...
She saw an opening and--
女士  计划有变
Ma'am, there's been a change of plans.
等等  什么计划有变
Uh, hold on. What change of plans?
我们带您回白宫
We're taking you back to the White House.
不  我们得去安德鲁斯空军基地
No, we're going to Andrews.
抱歉  这是总统的直接命令
I'm sorry, this is direct from the president.
这不会像看上去那么困难
This is not gonna be as difficult as it seems.
泰瑞明天一早就跟退伍军人事务处
Now, Terry's gonna be in touch with Veteran Affairs
那边接触  起草修正案
first thing tomorrow to draft an amendment.
如果共和党在委员会那里给我们阻力
And if the Republicans give us any resistance in committee,
我就开始打电话找人
I'll start making calls.
本轮会议结束之前
No reason why this can't get to the floor
完全可以呈递国会
before the end of the session.
谢谢你  总统先生
Well, thank you, Mr. President.
谢你自己  你这手玩得漂亮
Thank yourself. You played this well.
你怎么玩的
How did you play it?
那是我们的小秘密了
Well, now, that's our little secret, isn't it?
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
总统先生  我来吧
Uh, Mr. President, I got this.
克莱尔
Oh, Claire.
总统的讲话多棒啊
Didn't the president make the most wonderful speech?
是啊
Oh, he certainly did.
多谢你说服总统
And I thank you for convincing the president
在讲话中提到西莉娅
to mention Celia in his remarks.
不客气
Well, it was my pleasure.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
晚安  克莱尔
Good night, Claire.
我们说好的
We had a deal.
我来了
I showed up.
却利用这个机会给我的竞选拆台
And used that opportunity to undermine the campaign.
你为什么不问我
Why didn't you just ask me?
如果你需要用诊所打动桃瑞丝
If you needed the clinic to convince Doris--
你根本不希望我竞选  弗兰西斯
You don't want me to run, Francis.
是的  我不希望  但我们已经达成谅解了
That's right, I don't. But we'd reached an understanding.
我觉得你就是说了些讨好我的话
I think you said what you wanted me to hear.
那你误解我了
Well, then you misread me.
我是在替自己着想  你也一样
I am looking out for myself. Just like you are.
你为自己着想
And where did that get you,
而不是为我们两人着想的下场又如何
looking out for yourself instead of looking out for us?
30选区现在没希望了  你明白的
The 30th is dead now. You know that.
你觉得我会放弃吗
You think I'm giving up?
怎么  你要跟琼斯母女竞争吗
What, you're gonna run against the Joneses?
你会出丑的  克莱尔
You'll make a fool of yourself, Claire.
即便他们支持你  你的胜算都不大
The odds were against you even with their blessing.
我本希望你自己能明白
Now, I hoped you'd reach that conclusion on your own.
但你却对我撒谎
But instead, you lied to me.
我没法逼你想通道理
Now, I can't force you to see reason.
但我不允许你成为隐患
But I will not allow you to become dangerous.
我也来一杯
I'll take one.
喝我的吧
Take mine.
克莱尔  听我说
Claire, look...
我赢下大选后  我们就可以专注于
When I win the general, then we can concentrate
为你在德州赢得参议员席位
on a Senate seat for you in Texas.
你反正也不会想待在众议院
You don't want to be in the House, anyway.
我们两人都没想到会出现希瑟·邓巴
And neither of us could have predicted a Heather Dunbar,
那么厉害的对手
or how formidable she'd be.
我们现在是在搏命
We are fighting for our lives here.
等你竞选  你会希望处于有利地位
And when you run, you wanna do so from a position of strength.
这是个时机问题
It's about timing.
或许是太早了  或许你是对的
Maybe it's too soon. Maybe you're right.
但我得想想
But I need to think.
好吧
Fair enough.
我不能在这儿想
I can't do that here.
回德州吗
Back in Texas?
我不确定我得想多久
I'm not sure how long I'll need.
需要多久都行
Well, take as long as you want.
我该走了
I should get going.
已经挺晚了  你确定你不想留下过夜吗
It's late. You sure you don't want to spend the night?
-母亲还在等我回去  -好吧
- Well, Mother was expecting me. - All right.
我自己出去  你继续喝吧
I'll walk myself out. You enjoy your drink.
以前有个男孩
You know, there was a boy
就住在我加夫尼老家一个街区外的地方
that lived down the street from me in Gaffney.
跟我年纪差不多  他叫沃特·莱森
About my age. His name was Walter Wryson.
他以前经常从家里跑出来  来我们家
He used to run away from home all the time and come to our house.
并没什么充分的缘由
Not for any good reason.
他爸爸不打他  也不愁吃穿
His daddy didn't beat him. He had clothes on his back.
莱森一家比我们有钱多了
The Wrysons had way more money than we did,
但他还是要逃家
but run away he would,
每个月至少一次  直接跑来我们家
at least once a month and come straight to our place.
一般  我母亲会打给他母亲
Now, usually, my mother would call his mother
然后她就会来接他
and she'd come and fetch him.
但到了第九第十次时
But about the ninth or tenth time this happened,
沃特跑到外面  爬上了我们后院的一棵树
Walter ran outside, climbed up into a tree in our backyard,
无论如何不肯下来
and wouldn't come down for nothing.
我妈妈跟他妈妈说
Now, my mama said to his mama,
"你让他在我们这儿待会儿吧
"Why don't you let us keep him for a while,
直到他肯回家了"
until he feels like coming home?"
但是  那小子可真是倔
But man, oh, man, that boy was stubborn.
到了晚上  他还在树上
Night came, and he was still up there.
不吃不喝  不拉屎
No food, no water... no toilet.
我去睡觉之前
And just before I went to bed,
我往窗外看  听到了他的哭声
I looked out my window and I heard him crying.
我说  "沃特  你为什么不下来呢"
And I said, "Walter, why don't you come on down?"
他就摇头  不肯
And he just shook his head no.
第二天早晨  我醒来  往窗外一看
Well, the next morning, I woke up, I looked out the window
沃特还在树上
and Walter was still up in that tree.
于是早饭之后  我拿着一盘鸡蛋过去
So after breakfast, I walked over with a plate of eggs...
问他是否想来点
and I asked him if he wanted some.
他又摇头
And again, he just shook his head.
我生气了
And I got angry.
那小子有个好房子  好家庭
That boy had a good house, a good family,
我求之不得的那种
the sort I would've killed for,
他自己却不自知
and he didn't even realize it.
于是我去工具棚  拿来把斧子
So I went into the tool shed and I took out an ax.
我对沃特说
And I said to Walter...
"你想知道住在我家究竟是什么感觉吗"
"You want to know what it's really like to live at my house?"
我一顿狂砍那棵树
And I gave that tree a good whack.
沃特大喊  但我没停手
And Walter cried out, but I kept on.
你从没听过
I mean, you've never heard
我砍树时  沃特发出的
screams like the one coming from Walter
那样的尖叫
as I chopped at that tree.
他都尿裤子了
He pissed his pants,
淋了下来
and it came raining down on the ground,
但我毫不在乎
but I didn't pay it no mind.
我还继续砍
I just kept whacking away.
于是
Well...
没过多久沃特就下来了
it didn't take long before Walter was on the ground
跑回了自己家
and running back to his house.
瞧  他不过就是需要点动力
You see, all he needed was a little motivation.
所以我可以给克莱尔时间
So I'll give Claire some time.
但为了她好
But for her sake,
希望她能在我拿出斧子之前
I hope she comes out of her tree
就从她的树上下来
before I have to bring out my ax.
他要我等着竞选参议员
He wants me to hold off for Senate.
我告诉他我会考虑的
I told him I would think about it.
-那么结束了吗  -不  没结束
- So it's over? - Oh, no, it's not over.
他在全国电视上表示支持西莉娅
He endorsed Celia on national television.
别去想30选区了
Forget the 30th.
我们得往大想  就在本轮
We need to think bigger. This cycle.
那我们得好好谈谈我的酬金问题了
Then we need to talk seriously about my compensation.
-接通了吗  -是  先生
- He on? - Yes, sir.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我这就给您接  先生
I'll connect you now, sir.
佩特罗夫总统  您现在在跟总统通话了
President Petrov, you are now on with the president.
晚上好  总统先生
Good evening, Mr. President.
早上好  总统先生
Good morning, Mr. President.
你的讲话很棒
Your speech was good.
或许有点太...
Perhaps, a bit too...
乐观了
optimistic, hmm?
我说的关于俄罗斯的话都是真心的
I meant what I said about Russia.
那只是空谈  没多大意义
It's just words. They mean very little.
我愿意用实际行动支持我的言论
I'm willing to back them up with action.
首先  我们该谈谈救市计划
First, we should talk about a bailout.
我愿意跟国际货币基金组织合作  帮你拿到所需
I'm willing to work with the IMF to get you what you need.
其次  作为示好
And second, as a gesture of good faith,
我们愿把伊戈尔·米尔金还给俄罗斯
we'd like to return Igor Milkin to Russia.
你早该送他回来了
You should've done so already.
我需要你保证他会得到审判
I need your assurances he'll get a trial.
-你在乎伊戈尔·米尔金干吗  -我不在乎
- What do you care about Igor Milkin? - I don't.
你就是把他送去西伯利亚
You can send him to Siberia
让他在矿井里死于黑肺病  我都不在乎
and let him die of black lung in a coal mine, for all I care.
但我在乎你的经济
But I do care about your economy.
你继续这么杀害受瞩目的商人
You keep killing high-profile businessmen
查抄他们的财产
and seizing their assets.
-那样不...  -你是说叛徒吧
- That's no-- - You mean, traitors?
听着  我知道他们在密谋造反
Look, I am aware that they were plotting a coup,
但那还是不...
but that still doesn't--
是的  因为是你策划的
Yes, because you orchestrated it.
-什么  -否则米尔金为什么要飞去美国
- Excuse me? - Why else would Milkin fly to America?
这事跟我们完全无关
We had nothing to do with this.
你...在约旦河谷的事上就跟我撒过谎
You... you lied to me about the Jordan Valley,
你在迈克尔·科里根的事上跟我撒了谎
you lied to me about Michael Corrigan.
我不是想要推翻你  维克多
I am not trying to replace you, Viktor.
我是想帮你  但你也得帮我
I'm trying to help you. But you have to help me.
石油减产这样的威胁不会好使的
These threats of reducing your oil production, it won't work.
你以为抬升能源价格会伤到我们
You think jacking up energy prices is gonna hurt us,
但那只是敲诈
but it's just extortion.
我不会向敲诈低头的
And I will not respond to extortion.
我可以把你的叛徒送回去
Now, I'll send your traitor back,
但你不能再
but you've got to stop
查抄公司  把人变没了
seizing companies and making people disappear.
伊戈尔·米尔金比叛徒还糟糕  他是美国的傀儡
Igor Milkin is worse than a traitor. He's an American puppet.
改朝换代  那才是敲诈
Regime change, that's extortion.
是啊  但那是他们自己的行为  你是多虑了
Yes, but they acted on their own. You're being paranoid.
送他回来  别开条件
Send him back. No terms.
你如果不肯谈判  我们不会有进展的
We're not going to get anywhere if you're not willing to negotiate.
那...
Well...
我们没话可说了
then I believe we're finished.
是没什么可说了  谢谢  总统先生
And I believe you're right. Thank you, Mr. President.
把米尔金安置在安全地点  他哪都不能去
Put Milkin in a secure location. He's not going anywhere.
米尔金先生
Mr. Milkin.
请你跟我来
I need you to come with me.
我们去哪
Where are we going?
羁押设施
A detainment facility.
我不是要被遣返吧
I'm not being deported, am I?
不  我们要处理你的庇护请求
No, we're going to process your asylum request.
克莱尔
Claire?
如果你想抽烟  就抽吧
If you wanna smoke, you should smoke.
我就是想抽一口
I only wanted one drag.
他讨厌你以前拿着烟去马厩
He hated how you used to go down to the stables with your cigarettes.
我不知道他知道这事
I didn't realize he knew.
他那么爱你  你杀人他都不会在乎
He adored you. You got away with murder.
你一直没睡等着我吗
Did you wait up for me?
不  是药的关系
No, it's the medication.
让我整天都感觉疲惫  然后又整宿睡不着
Keeps me tired all day, and then I'm up all night.
我...看了讲话
I... I watched the speech.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
很晚了  母亲  我们早上再谈吧
It's late, Mother. Let's talk in the morning.
对了  耳环真漂亮  我在电视上注意到了
By the way, those earrings are beautiful. I noticed 'em on TV.
是弗兰西斯母亲的耳环
They're Francis' mother's earrings.
-貌似不止一克拉  -两克拉
- They look like they're over a carat. - Two carats.
她肯定从谁那儿偷来的
No doubt she stole them from someone.
安德伍德一家永远能让人吃惊
The Underwoods never cease to amaze.
母亲
Mother...
我需要点钱
I'm going to need some money.
给诊所吗  不是...
For the clinic? Isn't--
150万  给莉安  还额外再需要一点
A million five for LeAnn and some on top of that.
我以为你的竞选没戏了
Well, I thought your campaign was dead.
是的  但我还是需要她为我工作
It is, but I still need her to work for me.
但做什么呢  我可以向我的朋友借钱
But, what for? I mean, I can't ask my friends for money and--
我们的钱
Our money.
你是指我的钱
You mean my money.
别跟我争
Don't fight me on this.
爸爸会毫不犹豫地给我
Daddy would've done it, no questions asked.
是啊  我没他那么傻
Yes, well... I'm not as foolish as he was.
那我只能卖掉地产了
Well, I'll just have to sell the estate.
什么
You what?
钱在信托里  但地产是在我名下
The money is in the trust, but the land is in my name.
-你不会敢的  -我在求你帮忙
- You wouldn't dare. - Well, I'm asking for your help.
-如果你不肯  -帮忙
- If you refuse to give it-- - Help?
我生病时你可完全没帮过我
You didn't lift a finger to help me when I got sick.
你没告诉我你病了
You didn't tell me you were sick!
因为你已经背弃了我
Because you had turned your back on me!
你是那么让人失望
Oh, you are such a disappointment.
你不希望我背着你卖掉房子  但我会的
You don't want me to sell this house out from under you, but I will.
我是你母亲
I am the mother.
I am the mother!
国情咨文讲话一般在每年年初一二月份  国会复会后举行
其性质相当于"政府工作报告"
美国宪法规定  总统需定期向国会汇报国家发展和政府运行的状况
每年总统会借此机会  回顾总结过去一年或数年的政府工作
同时公布新一年政府的施政纲领
程序上  首先每年年初
众议院议长要代表国会向总统发出正式邀请  然后白宫接受邀请
发表国情咨文讲话当晚  总统及内阁成员会前往国会山
出席讲话的还有  最高法院的大法官
参谋长联席会议主席等三军统帅  以及国会两院的议员们
每逢此时  总统和议员们会有机会邀请一些嘉宾一同出席
受邀者往往是总统某项政策的受益者
这样他们在转播出镜时  会提醒观众政府在过去一年中的建树
由于美国两党斗争激烈
所以议员们在台下落座时会根据自己党派归属而分开就座
总统在台上讲到某项政策和议题时  同党派议员会起立欢呼
而对立党派的议员们则端坐不动  面无表情
剧中民主党丢了国会多数席位  所以议长是共和党人
安德伍德讲话时可以看到同党派的副总统起立鼓掌
而共和党的议长则没什么反应
由于国情咨文是美国政坛一年一度的盛事
所以第一夫人的着装也是媒体和观众关注的焦点
2016年奥巴马最后一次国情咨文讲话时
第一夫人米歇尔·奥巴马所穿的黄色礼服  就非常引人注目
奥巴马的讲话还没结束  这款价格不菲的礼服便在网上被抢购一空